A Guide to the Arena Stage Collection: Stage Manager Reports 1950-2000
George Mason University Libraries
Special Collections and Archives, George Mason University
Arena Stage Collection: Stage Manager Reports 1950-2000
Special Collections and Archives, George Mason University
Arena0015
11 boxes comprising 6 cubic feet (9 linear feet)
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open to research.
Acquisition Information
Donated by Arena Stage in the fall of 2000
Historical Information
Arena Stage was an early leader in the resident theater movement. One of the first not-for-profit theaters in the United States as well as a pioneer of the regional theater movement the Arena Stage was the first regional theater to transfer a production to Broadway, the first invited by the U.S. State Department to tour behind the Iron Curtain and the first to receive a Tony Award. Co-founded in 1950 by Edward Mangum a teacher from the George Washington University, and Zelda Fichandler one of his students, Arena Stage was opened in Washington D.C. to fill the void left by the closing of the National Theater in 1948. Deriving it's name from the idea of "theater in the round," Arena Stage became one of the first resident theaters in the United States, beginning with a company of only eight actors. Today, Arena performs to over 250,000 patrons during a September to June season and employs nearly 200 theater professionals and craft persons, who are responsible for all the costumes and scenery seen on stage. Many now- famous actors took part in Arena Stage productions during the early part of their careers. Some of them include Robert Prosky, Morgan Freeman, Dianne Weist, James Earl Jones, Kevin Kline, Christopher Guest, Yeardly Smith and Samuel L. Jackson. Donated to George Mason University in fall of 2000, the Arena Stage Collection contains materials spanning the theater's 50 year history including production notebooks, photographs, playbills, scrapbooks, scripts and handwritten correspondence and other production materials.
Scope and Content
This series contains stage manager's reports for select productions, 1950-2000.
Arrangement
Alphabetical by production title
Contents List
- Arena Stage Collection: Stage Manager Reports
  - Stage Manager's Report: After the Fall; '79-'80 (Box Box 1)
  - Ah Wilderness! 1978-1979 (Box Box 1)
  - All the Kings Men, 1987-188 (Box Box 1)
  - American Buffalo; 1980-1981 (Box Box 1)
  - American Splendor, 1987-1988 (Box Box 1)
  - An American Tragedy 1979-1980 (Box Box 1)
  - The Andersonville Trial; 1966-1967 (Box Box 1)
  - Animal Crackers 1981-1982 (Box Box 1)
  - Accent of Mt. Fuji 1974-1975 (Box Box 1)
  - As You Like It '83-'84 (Box Box 1)
  - Autumn Garden '76-'77 (Box Box 1)
  - Awake and Sing; 1970-1971 (Box Box 1)
  - Beyond Therapy '83-'84 (Box Box 1)
  - Billy Bishop Goes to War (Box Box 1)
  - Blood Knot (Box Box 1)
  - Boccaccio (Box Box 1)
  - Briar Patch 1988-1989 (Box Box 1)
  - Candide 1982-1983 (Box Box 1)
  - Casualties 1978-1979 (Box Box 1)
  - Catsplay 1976-1977 (Box Box 1)
  - Checkmates 1987-1988 (Box Box 1)
  - The Chemmy Circle 1969-1970 (Box Box 1)
  - The Cherry Orchard 1969-1970 (Box Box 1)
  - The Cherry Orchard 1987-1988 (Box Box 1)
  - The Child 1980-1981 (Box Box 1)
  - A Chorus of Disapproval 1988-1989 (Box Box 1)
  - Cloud 9 (Box Box 1)
  - Coconuts 1987-1988 (Box Box 1)
  - Cold Storage 1980-1981 (Box Box 1)
  - Comedians 1977-1978 (Box Box 1)
  - Conflict of Interest 1971-1972 (Box Box 1)
  - Conquest of the South Pole 1989-1990 (Box Box 1)
  - Crime and Punishment 1986-1987 (Box Box 1)
  - The Crucible 1966-1967 (Box Box 1)
  - The Crucible 1986-1987 (Box Box 1)
  - Curse of the Starving Class 1978-1979 (Box Box 1)
  - Cymbeline 1982-1983 (Box Box 1)
  - Dance of Death 1969-1970 (Box Box 1)
  - Dandelion Wine 1975-1976 (Box Box 1)
  - Death of a Salesman (Box Box 1)
  - A Delicate Balance 1981-1982 (Box Box 1)
  - Design for Living 79-80 (Box Box 1)
  - Disability: A Comedy 1978-1979 (Box Box 1)
  - Disability 1980-1981 (Box Box 1)
  - Don Juan 1978-1979 (Box Box 1)
  - Duck hunting 1977-1978 (Box Box 1)
  - The Dubbuk 1974-1975 (Box Box 1)
  - Edith Stein 1969-1970 (Box Box 1)
  - Emigres 1979-1980 (Box Box 1)
  - Enchanted Night/The Police (Box Box 1)
  - Enemies 1972-1973 (Box Box 1)
  - Enemy of the People 1975-1976 (Box Box 1)
  - Enrico IV 1987-1988 (Box Box 1)
  - Execution of Justice 1984-1985 (Box Box 1)
  - Fences 1989-1990 (Box Box 1)
  - Hamlet: restricted correspondence; 1978 (Box Box 2)
  - Forever Yours; 1976-1977 (Box Box 2)
  - The Foursome 1972-1973 (Box Box 2)
  - The Front Page 1974-1975 (Box Box 2)
  - The Front Page 1974-1975 (Box Box 2)
  - Galileo 1980-1981 (Box Box 2)
  - Gemini 1977-1978 (Box Box 2)
  - Geniuses 1982-1983 (Box Box 2)
  - The Glass Menagerie 1989-1990 (Box Box 2)
  - Glengary Glen Ross 1986-1987 (Box Box 2)
  - God Bless You, Mr. Rosewater 1980-1981 (Box Box 2)
  - Good Person of Setzuan 1985-1986 (Box Box 2)
  - Gospel at Colonus 1984-1985 (Box Box 2)
  - Great White Hope 1967-1968 (Box Box 2)
  - Hamlet 1977-1978 (Box Box 2)
  - Happy End 1983-1984 (Box Box 2)
  - Heart Break House 1975-1976 (Box Box 2)
  - Heart Break House 1986-1987 (Box Box 2)
  - History of the American Film 1976-1977 (Box Box 2)
  - The Hostage 1972-1973 (Box Box 2)
  - The House of Blue Leaves 1971-1972 (Box Box 2)
  - Idiots Delight 1978-1979 (Box Box 2)
  - The Immigrant 1987-1988 (Box Box 2)
  - The Importance of Being Ernest 1987-1988 (Box Box 2)
  - School for Wives 1950-1951 (Box Box 2)
  - Separations 1977-1978 (Box Box 2)
  - Serjeant Musgraves Dance 1965-1966 (Box Box 2)
  - Sign in Sidney/Brustein's Window 1970-1971 (Box Box 2)
  - Singers 1976-1977 (Box Box 2)
  - Six Characters in Search of an Author 1988-1989 (Box Box 2)
  - The Skin of our Teeth 1965-1966 (Box Box 2)
  - Stand-up Tragedy 1989-1990 (Box Box 2)
  - Starting Here, Starting Now 1977-1978 (Box Box 2)
  - Status Quo Vadis 1971-1972 (Box Box 2)
  - Still Life 1982-1983 (Box Box 2)
  - Stray Dogs 1985-1986 (Box Box 2)
  - Streamers 1976-1977 (Box Box 2)
  - A Street Car Named Desire 1977-1978 (Box Box 2)
  - The Suicide 1980-1981 (Box Box 2)
  - Tales from the Vienna Woods 1978-1979 (Box Box 2)
  - The Taming of the Shrew 1985-1986 (Box Box 2)
  - Tartuffe 1984-1985 (Box Box 2)
  - Terbele and Her Demon 1979-1980 (Box Box 2)
  - The Tenth Man 1967-1968 (Box Box 2)
  - Three Men on a Horse 1973-1974 (Box Box 2)
  - Three Sisters 1983-1984 (Box Box 2)
  - Tin Types 1978-1979 (Box Box 2)
  - Tom 1973-1974 (Box Box 2)
  - Tom Foolery 1981-1982 (Box Box 2)
  - The TOT Family 1975-1976 (Box Box 2)
  - Trappers 1977-1978 (Box Box 2)
  - Tricks 1971-1972 (Box Box 2)
  - Twelfth Night 1971-1972 (Box Box 2)
  - Undiscovered Country 1981-1982 (Box Box 2)
  - Uptight 1971-1972 (Box Box 2)
  - Waiting for Godot 1975-1976 (Box Box 2)
  - A Walk in the Woods 1988-1989 (Box Box 2)
  - What the Butler Saw 1980-1981 (Box Box 2)
  - Who's Afraid of Virginia Wolf? 1974-1975 (Box Box 2)
  - The Wild Duck 1985-1986 (Box Box 2)
  - The Winter's Tale 1979-1980 (Box Box 2)
  - Wipe Out Games 1970-1971 (Box Box 2)
  - Living Stage Production Reports 1985-1986 (Box Box 3)
  - Living Stage Production Reports 1985-1986 (Box Box 3)
  - "Images", script 1985 (Box Box 3)
  - "Longstreet", script 1986 (Box Box 3)
  - "Images", Production materials (Box Box 3)
  - "Every Heart in the House", Production information (Box Box 3)
  - Room Service 1967-1968 (Box Box 4)
  - The Ruling Class 1970-1971 (Box Box 4)
  - Saint Joan 1976-1977 (Box Box 4)
  - A Public Prosecutor is Sick of it All 1972-1973 (Box Box 4)
  - Pueblo 1970-1971 (Box Box 4)
  - A Raisin in the Sun 1972-1973 (Box Box 4)
  - Real Estate 1984-1985 (Box Box 4)
  - Saturday, Sunday and Monday 1976-1977 (Box Box 4)
  - K-2 1981-1982 (Folder box 4)
  - Inherit the Wind 1973-1974 (Box Box 4)
  - The Inspector General 1966-1967 (Box Box 4)
  - Isn't it Romantic? (Box Box 4)
  - Julius Caesar 1974-1975 (Box Box 4)
  - Arturo UI (Box Box 4)
  - Restoration 1985-1986 (Box Box 4)
  - Ring Around the Moon 1988-1989 (Box Box 4)
  - Rivers and Ravines 1987-1988 (Box Box 4)
  - Major Barbara 1967-1968 (Box Box 4)
  - Major Barbara 1981-1982 (Box Box 4)
  - Madmen 1975-1976 (Box Box 4)
  - The Magistrate (Box Box 4)
  - Lower Depths 1976-1977 (Box Box 4)
  - MacBeth 1966-1967 (Box Box 4)
  - Lessons From Aloes 1981-1982 (Box Box 4)
  - Light Up the Sky 1987-1988 (Box Box 4)
  - Living at Home 1976-1977 (Box Box 4)
  - Look Back in Anger 1966-1967 (Box Box 4)
  - Loose Ends 1978-1979 (Box Box 4)
  - Long Days Journey into Night 1975-1976 (Box Box 4)
  - The Last Meeting of the Knights of the White Magnolia 1974-1975 (Box Box 4)
  - Leonce and Lena 1973-1974 (Box Box 4)
  - Les Blancs 1987-1988 (Box Box 4)
  - The Lesson 1965-1966 (Box Box 4)
  - Juno and the Paycock 1989-1990 (Box Box 4)
  - Mother Courage 1970-1971 (Box Box 5)
  - Measure for Measure (Box Box 5)
  - Marriage of Bette and Boo 1986-1987 (Box Box 5)
  - Prospect Mortality 1965-1966 (Box Box 5)
  - Exhibition, Scooping 1976-1977 (Box Box 5)
  - Poor Bitos (Box Box 5)
  - Plenty 1979-1980 (Box Box 5)
  - Playboy of the West Indies 1988-1989 (Box Box 5)
  - Plays and other Plays 1976-1977 (Box Box 5)
  - Merrily We Roll Along 1989-1990 (Box Box 5)
  - A Mid-Summers Nights Dream 1981-1982 (Box Box 5)
  - Moonchildren 1971-1972 (Box Box 5)
  - Passion Play 1984-1985 (Box Box 5)
  - Pantomime 1980-1981 (Box Box 5)
  - Our Town (Box Box 5)
  - Pantagleize 1971-1972 (Box Box 5)
  - On the Town 1988-1989 (Box Box 5)
  - Ourselves Alone 1986-1987 (Box Box 5)
  - Our Town 1972-1973 (Box Box 5)
  - The Piggy Bank 1986-1987 (Box Box 5)
  - The Philadelphia Story 1985-1986 (Box Box 5)
  - Nothing Sacred 1988-1989 (Box Box 5)
  - Oba Kosa 1974-1975 (Box Box 5)
  - One Flew Over the Cookoos Nest (Box Box 5)
  - Once in a Lifetime 1975-1976 (Box Box 5)
  - Old Times 1985-1986 (Box Box 5)
  - Of Thee I Sing 1992-1993 (Box Box 5)
  - Man Who Came to Dinner 1980-1981 (Box Box 5)
  - Man and Superman 1984-1985 (Box Box 5)
  - Nightclub Cantata (Box Box 5)
  - Night Mother (Box Box 5)
  - The Night Thoreau Spent in Jail 1970-1971 (Box Box 5)
  - The 1940's Radio Hour (Box Box 5)
  - No Place to Be Somebody 1969-1970 (Box Box 5)
  - Molly Sweeney 1996-1997 (Box Box 6)
  - A Month in the Country 1994-1995 (Box Box 6)
  - Mrs. Klein 1991-1992 (Box Box 6)
  - My Children, My Africa 1990-1991 (Box Box 6)
  - The Odyssey 1994-1995 (Box Box 6)
  - Of Thee I Sing 1992-1993 (Box Box 6)
  - Our Town 1990-1991 (Box Box 6)
  - A Perfect Ganesh 1994-1995 (Box Box 7)
  - Playquest 1995-1996 (Box Box 7)
  - The Plough and the Stars 1995-1996 (Box Box 7)
  - The Price 1993-1994 (Box Box 7)
  - Pygmalion 1990-1991 (Box Box 7)
  - The Revengers Comedies 1993-1994 (Box Box 7)
  - A Room of One's Own 1993-1994 (Box Box 7)
  - Room Service 1997-1998 (Box Box 7)
  - Seagull 1990-1991 (Box Box 7)
  - She Stoops to Conquer 1990-1991 (Box Box 7)
  - Skin of our Teeth 1992-1993 (Box Box 7)
  - Small World 1993-1994 (Box Box 7)
  - Sunday in the Park with George 1996-1997 (Box Box 7)
  - Summer and Smoke 1992-1993 (Box Box 7)
  - Twelfth Night 1993-1994 (Box Box 8)
  - Trinidad Sisters 1990-1991 (Box Box 8)
  - Touch of the Poet 1997-1998 (Box Box 8)
  - The Time of Your Life 1991-1992 (Box Box 8)
  - What the Butler Saw 1994-1995 (Box Box 8)
  - Wonderful Life 1992-1993 (Box Box 8)
  - Yerma 1991-1992 (Box Box 8)
  - You Can't Take it With You 1993-1994 (Box Box 8)
  - Way of the World 1992-1993 (Box Box 8)
  - Waiting Room 1995-1996 (Box Box 8)
  - Voir-Dire 1996-1997 (Box Box 8)
  - Vivisections of the Blown Mind 1990-1991 (Box Box 8)
  - The Visit 1991-1992 (Box Box 8)
  - Uncle Vanya 1997-1998 (Box Box 8)
  - Teen Mom 1991-1992 (Box Box 9)
  - Misc. Production Reports 1992-1993 (Box Box 9)
  - Misc. Production 1993-1994 (Box Box 9)
  - misc. Reports 1994-1995 (Box Box 9)
  - Misc. Production Reports 1995-1996 (Box Box 9)
  - Children First 1996 (Box Box 9)
  - Misc. Production Reports 1997-1998 (Box Box 9)
  - Production Reports 1998-1999 (Box Box 9)
  - Banjo Dancing 1981 (Box Box 10)
  - Babes in Boyland - S.M. Reports (Box Box 10)
  - Before it Hits Home 1990-1991 (Box Box 10)
  - Blues for an Alabama Sky 1996-1997 (Box Box 10)
  - Born Guilty 1990-1991 (Box Box 10)
  - Brother's Karamazov (Box Box 10)
  - Candide 1990-1991 (Box Box 10)
  - Caucasian Chalk Circle 1990-1991 (Box Box 10)
  - Cerceau 1990-1991 (Box Box 10)
  - Community Carol 1993-1994 (Box Box 10)
  - Dance of Death 1995-1996 (Box Box 11)
  - Dancing at Lugnasa 1993-1994 (Box Box 11)
  - A Doll House 1989-1990 (Box Box 11)
  - Dimly Perceived Threats to the System 1997-1998 (Box Box 11)
  - Dirty Work 1992-1993 (Box Box 11)
  - Ghosts 1996-1997 (Box Box 11)
  - Hedda Gabler 1994-1995 (Box Box 11)
  - House Arrests 1997-1998 (Box Box 11)
  - I Am a Man 1994-1995 (Box Box 11)
  - It Ain't Nothing but the Blues 1996-1997 (Box Box 11)
  - It's the Truth if you Thing it is 1992-1993 (Box Box 11)
  - Jar the Floor 1991-1992 (Box Box 11)
  - Long Day's Journey into Night 1994-1995 (Box Box 11)
  - Lovers and Executioners 1997-1998 (Box Box 11)
  - Matchmaker 1995-1996 (Box Box 11)
  - Misalliance 1994-1995 (Box Box 11)
  - The Miser 1995-1996 (Box Box 11)